翻译：Iz      Tiogy      红豆包
校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
更多动画  就在@欧美动漫汉化军团
《开心汉堡店》第五季第二十集
臭虫去死吧
除虫害公司
小东西
Hey, little guy,
你今天要成为美味汉堡的一部分了
you're gonna become part of a great burger today.
荣幸之至
I'm honored.
有名字吗
What are you calling it?
豆薯哒哒
Jicama-Tah-Ta.
太好笑了
Great joke!
请不要和食物交谈
No making the food talk, please.
现在知道为什么我是唯一
And you wonder why I'm the only one
愿意和你一起购物的人了吧
who'll go shopping with you.
老爸  看啊  等等  现在别看
Dad, look! Wait, don't look now.
-好了  现在看吧  -哪里
- Okay, now look. - Where?
-那里  -那是什么
- There. - Wh-What is it?
上了岁数的亚州人
An old Asian man?
不是
That's not an old Asian man.
-不是吗  -他是鹰
- It's not? -It's Hawk!
-鹰  -鹰  电影《鹰与雏》里的
- Hawk? - Hawk! From Hawk & Chick!
父亲  当心
Father, look out!
水母怪
The Jellyfish Monster!
多谢  雏
Thank you, Chick.
真实父女演驿的
Father-daughter samurai team
父女武士搭档
played by an actual father and daughter.
-这完全就是咱俩嘛  -我知道
-It's like they based it on us. - I know.
我们可以告他们
We could sue.
我们舍不得  因为我们好爱这电影
We won't, 'cause we love these movies.
但的确  这就是我们
But yeah, that's us.
但他的年龄对吗
But is he the right age?
他在最后一部电影里多大年龄
How old was he in his last movie?
他们和巨型蝴蝶恶战那集吗
The one where they fight the giant butterfly?
-是的  -应该有40岁了
- Yeah. - Probably 40.
刚才那人多少岁了  100吗
And how old is that guy, a hundred?
他没有100岁
He's not a hundred.
你都80岁了  他至少也得有90岁
Well, you're 80, so he's got to be at least 90.
可他来我们这破小镇干嘛呢
What's he doing in our dumb town, anyway?
也许他是特地从日本飞过来买我们的蘑菇
Maybe he flies from Japan to buy our mushrooms?
他离开市场了
He's leaving the market.
-我要大喊他的名字吗  -别
- Should I shout his name? - No.
我们还是别打扰他了
We should leave him alone.
或者我们可以跟踪他
Or we could follow him.
-我们已经这么做了  -这样真奇怪
- We kind of already are. - This is weird.
我们回家吧  好好过我们自己的生活
Let's go home, live our lives the best we can.
我们尽管穷  但也很快乐
I mean, we're poor, but we're happy.
-他过马路了  -快走  快走
- He's crossing the street! - Move! Move!
抱歉  多谢
Sorry. Thank you.
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
不  他上公车了
No! He's getting on a bus!
我们可不能跟着他上公车
Well, we're not getting on a bus to follow this guy.
我们还是下站就下吧
We should get off at the next stop.
我们认错人了
It's not him.
就是他
It's him!
真是冒险家鹰
It's Rising Hawk.
天呐  天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
你们父亲和妹妹到底去哪儿了
Where the hell are your father and your sister?
他们早就应该回来了
They should be back by now.
也许他们害怕呆在我身边
Maybe they're afraid to be around me.
因为我所向披靡[着火了]
'Cause I'm on fire.
游戏  布景  食盐
Game, set, salt.
她虽然做不来长除法
She can't do long division,
但滑盐瓶她可真是高手
but the girl can slide a saltshaker.
谁  我啊
Who? Oh, me.
我要去说点什么
I'm gonna say something.
你打算说什么
What are you gonna say?
先跟我练习一遍
Say it to me like you're gonna say it to him.
好吧
Okay, all right.
-你好  小岛先生  -太糟了
-Hi, Mr. Kojima... -Terrible.
-什么  -完菜
- What? - Bad.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Right, right, right.
还没准备好  还没准备好
Not ready. Not ready.
正派宾馆
-四层  -是的
- Fourth floor. -Yeah.
有楼梯  我们走
Stairs. Let's go.
等等  这太疯狂了
Wait, this is crazy.
我们有什么计划
What's our plan?
让他在你的豆薯上签名
Get him to sign your jicama?
我...我没笔
I don't... I don't have a pen.
你们为什么跟踪我
Why are you follow me?
开个玩笑  开个玩笑
Joking! Joking!
很  很有创意
Oh. Oh, that-that's good.
-你真吓到我们了  -我吓到你了吗
- Y-You got us. - Did I get you?
是的  吓傻了
Yeah, very much.
我的小心脏跳得可快了
My little heart is beating so fast.
没错
Yeah.
吓得我掉了豆薯
I dropped my jicama.
你是小岛信治吗
so... Shinji Kojima?
叫我小岛就好了  或者阿岛
Please, call me Kojima... or Koji.
但如果我欠你钱的话就别叫了
Just don't call me if I owe you money.
我欠别人挺多钱的
I owe people money.
我叫鲍勃
My name is Bob.
这是我的女儿  露易丝
and this is my daughter, Louise.
我们看过你所有的电影
We've seen all your movies.
我是在尖叫吗
Am I screeching?
-我感觉自己有点失控了  -是的
- I feel like I'm screeching a little. - Yes.
抱歉  你对我们意义重大
Sorry, you're kind of a big deal for us.
真高兴有人认出我来
It's nice to get recognized.
我们很好奇  你来我们镇里干嘛
We were wondering... why are you in our town?
你迷路了吗
Did you get lost?
好多人来这里都是因为他们迷路了
Lots of people are here because they got lost.
没有迷路  我是来找...
Not lost. Just looking...
好吧
Okay.
等等  那是什么意思
Wait, what-what does that mean?
你貌似话没说完
You kind of trailed off there.
我说得太多了
I have, uh, said too much.
你们知道什么好的餐厅吗
So, do you know a good place to eat?
知道  我们就开了家餐馆
Yes! Uh, we have a restaurant.
不  不  不  不  那并不好
No, no, no, no! It's not good!
真的很好
It's really good.
对阿岛来说不够好  老爸
It's not good enough for Koji, Dad!
到底好还是不好呢
Is it good or not good?
-很好  -不够好
- Good. - Not good.
- Good. - Oh, not good.
很好
Good.
明星原来是这样咀嚼食物的
Wow, so that's how celebrities chew their food.
我大错特错了
I was all wrong.
明星嚼食
Celebrity Chewing!
要有这表演我很愿意看看
I'd watch that show.
蒂娜  再给我和阿岛拍张合影
Tina, take another picture of me with Koji.
我们做那种表情
Let's do one where we're laughing
我刚说了件很好笑的事情
at a hilarious thing I just said.
但有点太深奥了  你起先没明白
But it's so smart you don't get it
接着你就懂了
for a second, and then you do.
现在我明白了
Oh, now I get it.
他明白了  他明白了
Oh, he just got it. He just got it.
等我出名了  我会雇一个人
When I'm famous, I'll have a handler whose only job
专门阻止像老妈这样的人靠近我
will be to keep people like Mom away from me.
-也许也包括老妈  -什么
- And Mom, too, maybe. - What?
开玩笑  你知道你到时会住在我的拖车里的
Just kidding. You know you'll live in my trailer.
我也想要一张
I want a copy of that one.
我们不洗照片
Oh, we don't print our photos.
我们就让它们待在相机里
They live in the camera.
伙计们  我搬来了
Guys, here it is!
我们从电视上录的所有的《鹰与雏》电影
All the Hawk & Chicks we recorded from TV.
我们有很多选择
We've got a lot to choose from.
《鹰与雏之大战鲨鱼人》
Hawk & Chick versus Sharkman
或是经典的《鹰与雏之大战付丧神》
or the classic Hawk & Chick versus Tsukumogami.
付丧神是什么
What's a Tsukumogami?
一种每百年复活一次的东西
It's just an object that comes to life every hundred years.
在这部电影里  它是棵树
And in this case, it's a tree.
他们和一棵树作战吗  酷
So, they fight a tree? Cool.
远不止这些  蒂娜
Well, there's more to it than that, Tina.
讲的是一名理发师和他的女儿
It's about a barber and his daughter traveling
跋涉于村落间  试图远离麻烦
from village to village, trying to avoid trouble...
但麻烦总是找上门来
But trouble always finds them.
于是他们就给麻烦厉害看看
And then they kick trouble's ass!
我说的对吗  我在看你哦  阿岛
Am I right? Looking at you, Koji.
我在回看你  露易丝
Looking back at you, Louise.
等等  这些电影都是关于理发师
Wait, so these movies are about traveling barbers
和奇怪的日本怪物作战的故事吗
who fight weird Japanese monsters?
相当于没有爱情戏的《绿巨人》吗
So, it's like a less sexual Incredible Hulk?
那不是树  那是个怪物
That's not a tree. That's a monster.
这真是太神奇了
This is amazing.
我们在和鹰一起看《鹰与雏》
We're watching a Hawk & Chick with Hawk!
我知道  他一定也因为
I know, and he must be excited
和我们一起看超兴奋的
'cause he's watching it with us.
也许并没有  他哭了
Or not. He's crying.
你还好吗  小岛
Everything okay, Kojima?
不  不太好
No. Not okay.
我来你们镇是为了找我的小雪
The reason I'm in your town is to find my Yuki.
那是日本话里找回昔日光辉的意思吗
Is that Japanese for getting your groove back?
不  那是英语里找回我女儿的意思
No. It is English for getting my daughter back.
小雪  你的女儿住这里吗
Yuki? Your daughter lives here?
是的  没错
Yes, she does.
我还没有勇气和她讲话
I haven't gathered the courage to speak to her.
我已经30年都没有和小雪讲话了
I haven't spoken to Yuki in 30 years.
鹰与雏居然30年都没有讲话了
Hawk and Chick haven't spoken in 30 years?!
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
我和妻子离婚后
She chose to move to America
她就选择和母亲搬去美国了
with her mother after we divorced.
我们的关系很紧张
Our relationship was strained
都是我一手造成的
because I strained it.
现在小雪是名会计
Now Yuki is... an accountant.
-什嘛  -真好
- What?! - Oh, nice.
我大老远跑过来
I've come all this way,
但我担心小雪不想见我
but I worry Yuki doesn't want to see me.
30年算什么
Eh, what's 30 years?
我有件内衣年龄都比这长
I got underwear older than that.
你俩很快就会重新并肩作战的
You two will be sword-fighting together in no time.
我们得成全此事
We've got to make this samur-ight!
我有个很棒的主意  但你们不会喜欢
I've got a great idea you're all gonna hate.
家庭会议
Family conference.
别担心
Don't worry.
一点都不无礼  一点都不
Doesn't seem rude. No, no.
也许我们要做的就是去找到小雪
Maybe all we need to do is get Yuki
让她再次在大屏幕上
to see her dad as Hawk again.
看到她父亲扮演鹰的样子
Up on the big screen!
好吧  但我们要怎么做呢
Okay, but how do we do that?
我真是好喜欢这样挤在一起
I'm really enjoying this huddle.
有史以来最棒的一次
One of the best huddles ever.
还行吧
It's all right.
各位  下面就是你们不会喜欢的部分了
Guys, this is the part you're gonna hate.
我们得举办《鹰与雏》影展
We got to put on a Hawk & Chick film festival
说服他们俩个都参加
and convince them both to go.
然后重聚
Reunion! Boom!
你不喜欢  你也不喜欢
You hate it, you hate it.
-我没不喜欢  -我喜欢
- I don't hate it. - I like it.
-我很喜欢  -我也很喜欢
- I love it. - I love it, too.
你偷偷挤进来了
Oh! You snuck in the huddle!
我没有番茄酱了
I am out of ketchup.
但我会参加这个影展的
But I am in for the festival.
*爱的武士影展*
*Samurai festival of love. *
你们是想这整个周末包场
So, you want me to let you guys take over the theater
连映70年代一部根本不出名的
for the entire weekend for a marathon
什么武士电影
of some obscure samurai movies from the '70s.
是吗
Is that right?
-对  你同意了  - 没门
- Yup. So we're good here? - Not gonna happen.
但是电影主演会来
But the stars of the movies are gonna be there.
很可能会来  至少有一位会
Most likely. Well, one is for sure.
重点是他们会在粉丝面前重聚
Point is they're gonna reunite in front of all their fans!
父女再相聚
Father and daughter together again...
你干嘛
What-what are you doing?
-没什么  继续  -你听得到我说话吗
- Oh, this? Nothing. Keep talking. - Can you still hear me?
关上窗户  再见了您呐
I'm just gonna close this down, and bye!
现在有点吵
It'a little crack now.
-好吧  谢谢你  -谢谢你
- Great. Thank you. - Thank you!
露易丝  走吧
Come on, Louise. Let's go.
是我在说话
Me. I'm talking.
小岛信治真的来了吗
Is Shinji Kojima really in town?
小雪也在
And Yuki?
当然  等等  你也看过《鹰与雏》
Yeah! Wait, so you know the Hawk & Chick movies?
我超爱看  很多人都喜欢看的
I love them! Lots of people do.
你要是办个《鹰与雏》影展
If you did a Hawk & Chick film festival,
一定会爆满
people would definitely show up.
那你能说服你老板
So, can you talk your boss into letting us
-让我们放电影吗  -不能
- use this theater? - No.
以前办的影展都很糟糕
We've had bad experiences doing film festivals.
办过梅格・瑞恩影展
We had a Meg Ryan film festival,
结束后这里变得好恶心
and this place was disgusting afterwards.
我们尽力了
Oh, well, we tried.
-谢谢  -等等  等等
- Thanks. - Wait, wait, wait.
你们可以在这里办影展
You can do the festival here.
就是得偷偷来
We just got to be sneaky.
像偷渡者一样小心
Like a coyote.
我喜欢这种感觉
Oh, I like the sound of this.
周六最后一场电影
Listen, the last show on Saturday night
晚上11点结束
lets out at 11:00.
等经理一走
Once my manager drives off,
剧院就是我们的了
the theater's ours.
到时候就可以秘密办一场
It'll be a secret, one night only,
《鹰与雏》系列影展  仅此一晚
midnight screening of a Hawk & Chick movie.
-行  同意  -太棒了
- Okay, we'll do it. - Yes!
谢谢  多米尼克  你还不赖嘛
Thanks, Dominic. You're all right.
你们有哪一部的碟
So which Hawk & Chick movies do you have prints of?
-碟  -嗯  碟片
- "Prints"? - Yeah, you know, a print?
放在投影仪里
Thing that goes in the projector?
投映到大屏幕上的
Makes pictures on the screen?
我们没有
Oh, we don't have one of those.
我们想的是带我们自己录的
No, we just thought we could bring our VHS tapes
广告部分快进
and just fast-forward through the commerci...
好吧  我也觉得这办法很糟
Okay, I realize how terrible that sounds.
我应该能找到
Maybe I can find one.
好吧  我今晚在电影论坛里找找
All right, you know, I'll poke around on some film forums.
你们该庆幸我今天正好打算上网
You're lucky I was planning to go online today.
好刺激
Exciting!
秘密武士影展之夜
An illegal samurai film festival!
这几个词我都好喜欢
I like all those words!
万事俱备  只欠电影
Now all we need is a movie.
还得说服小雪来和她父亲重聚
And we got to convince Yuki to want to reunite
她可能还恨着他呢
with her father, who she might hate.
我们还需要传单
And we need flyers!
秘密影展要怎么打广告
But how do we advertise a secret film screening?
奇幻码头
你喜欢电影吗
You like movies?
喜欢
Yeah, I like movies.
你酷吗
Are you cool?
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
算了  你走吧
Forget it! Keep moving.
-怎么样了  -有些人看着挺酷
- How's it going? - Some of these people seem cool,
但实际不是
but they're not!
-你怎么知道  -看到就知道
- How can you tell? - You can tell.
要扔垃圾桶吗
So, uh, trash can?
不  我觉得我们应该帮助这位日本老人
No. I think we owe it to an old Japanese man
和他已到中年的女儿
and his middle-aged daughter to see this through.
感动到我了
Wow, that just got me.
去社区大学试试吧
Let's try the quad at the community college.
那些白人最爱两样东西
There's two things those honkys love...
外国电影
foreign films and flyers telling them
以及告诉他们其它白人都去哪儿的传单
where other honkys will be!
一站式税务服务中心
这是小岛给的地址
Well, this is the address Kojima gave us.
在那里  是雏
That's her! That's Chick!
她竟然就这么坐在办公室里
It's so gross to see her behind a desk.
她本来应该去手刃雪怪
She should be slicing up the Snow Monster
或是六头相扑手的  太愚蠢了
or the Six-Headed Sumo! God, idiot!
等会别当着她面说她蠢
Please don't call her an idiot to her face.
要说现在赶紧说
Just get it out now.
蠢  蠢  蠢
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
走吧  咱去说服小雪参加影展
All right, let's go get Yuki to say yes to the fest.
-不去  -什么
- No. - What?
这么多年了
Look, I haven't even thought
我早就忘记这电影了
about those movies in years.
先冷静  我们可是在给你机会
Okay, okay, we're giving you a chance
找回当影星的感觉啊
to feel like a movie star again.
你又能在大荧幕上看到自己了
You can see yourself up on the big screen instead of staring
这可和在小屏幕上盯着那些数字不同
at that number screen on your desk there.
-我很喜欢会计的工作  -才不是
- I'm very happy as an accountant. - No, you're not.
-我喜欢  -你抑郁
- I am. - You're depressed.
-并没有  -我还没说完
- No, I'm not. - You didn't let me finish!
让我抑郁  你都让我抑郁了
"...ing" Me. Depressing me!
露易丝
Louise?
你见过哪个女儿和老爸拍了14部超赞的电影
I mean, who makes 14 amazing movies with their dad,
然后突然跑路的
and then just walks away one day?!
天理难容啊  小雪
Who does that, Yuki?
-露易丝  别说了  -天理难容
- Louise, stop. - Who does that?!
露易丝  我知道
Louise? I'm sure it wasn't easy
你以前和父亲共事不容易
working with your dad all those years.
我理解  我是过来人
I-I know. I get it. I've been there.
错  大错特错
Wrong. Wrong!
和老爸工作很有趣好吗
Working with your dad is fun.
我是说  和你老爸工作很有趣
I mean working with your dad was fun.
因为他是个武士  你们可以斩妖除魔
Because he was a samurai and you killed monsters!
小雪  我能和她谈谈吗
Yuki, um, can we have a minute, please?
露易丝  很明显她不想
Look, Louise, she obviously doesn't want
再见到她爸
to reconnect with her father.
我们应该取消影展
We should call off the screening.
啥  不行  我们必须让她去电影院
What? No way! We need to get her butt
让她给阿岛道歉
into that theater so she can apologize to Koji.
我觉得应该是小岛
I think it's more like Kojima
向小雪道歉才对  是他逼走小雪的
needs to apologize to Yuki for driving her away.
小雪不想过那样的生活
Yuki didn't want his life, Louise!
这么说我们达成一致了
So we're in agreement.
我们不告诉她她爸爸来了
We're not gonna tell her that her dad's here!
-什么  -我们骗骗她
- Wait. What? - We're gonna trick her.
-是吗  -嘘  她来了
- We are? - Shh, shh, shh! Here she comes.
那么电影展
So, about that film festival...
可以当作你同意了吗
can we put you down as a "Yes"?
我有同意么
I'm not so sure.
小雪  小雪  好啦  雪雪
Yuki, Yuki, come on, Yuke.
你就同意嘛
Just say yes.
想象一下  座无虚席的影院
Imagine a packed theater
全都是为你而来的影迷
of your adoring fans all there for you!
只为你  没有鹰  一整晚都属于你
Just you, no Hawk. It'll be Chick's night.
小雪  我们爱你
We love you, Yuki!
这是
What is...?
她是在模拟观众欢呼的场景
She's doing a... like, a lot of people cheering,
虽然听起来有些像鬼
but it sounds more like a ghost.
那你来  老爸  你来
Well, you do it, Dad. Can you do it.
不用了  我明白了
It's okay. I got it.
应该还挺有意思的
I guess that could be fun.
行吧  不管了  我去
All right, what the hell. I'll go.
-太好了  -太好了
- Great! - Great!
-搞定她了  -是
- So you got her to come? - Yup.
太棒
That's great.
你们有用我想的开场吗
Did you use my icebreaker?
-假装自己在打劫  -没有
- Pretend to rob the place? - No.
你有给自己的税款延期吗
Did you file for an extension on your taxes?
没有  蒂娜  那是假的  不能延期
No, Tina. That's a myth. You can't do that.
小雪听到要见父亲了  是什么心情
Well, how does Yuki feel about seeing her father?
我们貌似并没有告诉她她爸爸要来
We might not have told her that her dad was gonna be there.
-故意的无意之举  -什么
- On purpose by accident. - What?
-棒  你们骗了她  -没错
- Nice. You tricked her! - Yup.
没办法骗人团聚吧
I'm not sure you can trick people into reuniting.
可以的  梅尔・吉布森和丹尼・格洛弗
Not true. That's how they got Mel Gibson and Danny Glover
在《致命武器3》里就这么团聚的
back together for Lethal Weapon 3.
对  我也听说过
Yeah, I read that.
会成的
This is gonna work, people.
小雪会在影院里看《鹰与雏》
Yuki's gonna see Hawk & Chick up on the big screen,
然后像阿岛一样痛哭流涕
get all weepy like Koji did,
意识到自己的错误
and realize how crazy she's been,
我们就成英雄了  会被邀请到日本
and we're gonna be heroes, and we're gonna be invited
参加他们下一部电影的首映
to the premiere of their next movie in Japan!
我得去办护照了
I got to get a passport.
看看谁搞到了碟片  我
Guess who got the print. Me!
我爱死这家伙了
I freaking love this guy!
多米尼克  过来
Dominic! Ah, come here.
是哪一部
Which one is it?
《鹰与雏之大战海藻怪》
Hawk & Chick versus Seaweed Monster.
海藻怪  好怕怕
Seaweed Monster, scary!
唯一的问题是
Only thing...
这是日本原版35毫米碟片
it's an original 35 millimeter print from Japan.
太棒了
That's incredible.
我是说  原版  有点年头了
No, I mean, original, vintage.
没有英文配音
It's not dubbed in English.
连字幕都没有
It's not even subtitled.
-这样啊  -对
- Oh. - Yeah.
那你能搞个英文字幕吗
Well, so, can't you just whip up some English subtitles?
你以为随随便便就能往屏幕上打字吗
Oh, sure. Yeah, I'll just add some words to the screen.
这又不是未来世界
What do you think this is, future world?
我有个想法  跟这个没关系
I have an idea... not about this.
等等  还想到一个  跟这个有关
Okay, wait. No, I got one about this, too.
我想到六个
I have, like, six ideas.
第三个跟这个有关
The third one's about this.
自己配音  好想法
Dubbing it ourselves? Great idea.
谢谢  吉恩  好了啦
Thanks, Gene. Guys.
我把《鹰与雏大战海藻怪》的字幕
All right, I typed up all the subtitles
都打出来了
from Hawk & Chick versus Seaweed Monster.
你们知道拼写检查这个功能吗
Did you guys know about spell check?
超赞的
It's amazing.
每次打错它就会告诉你
It tells you if you misspell something.
当然有些还是有待商榷的
I mean, it's... Some of it is open to interpretation.
不过还挺有用
But, you know, it's helpful.
每个人负责的部分
Here's everyone's parts.
你负责几个角色
How many characters are you playing?
-三个  -三个挺好
- Three.  - three's good.
我是四个
I'm doing four characters,
不过也挺合理  我更有经验嘛
but I guess, you know, I'm more experienced.
但我有很多台词  因为我是村长
But I've got a lot of lines because I'm the mayor.
你是村长
You're the mayor?!
-鲍勃  她是村长  -琳  这不重要
- Bob, she's the mayor?! - Lin, it doesn't matter.
-蒂娜  蒂娜  让我当村长吧  -没门
- Tina, Tina, let me be the mayor. - Back off.
-开始吧  各位  -大显身手咯
- Let's dub, people! - Rub a dub dub!
这盏灯笼我们借给你们好多年了
It has been many days since we have loaned you our lantern.
现在能还给我们了吗
Can we have it back now?
-可以  -我发现这灯笼里的油
- Yes. - I see you are returning the lantern
比我借给你的时候少了
with less lantern oil than when I lent it to you.
还有  灯芯也需要更换了
Also, the wick is in need of replacement.
灯笼戏份好多啊
Lot of lantern talk.
一直很多
There's always a lot of lantern talk.
-你会喜欢上的  -已经迷上了
- You get into it. - Already there.
作为这个村的村长
As the mayor of this village...
老妈  走开  我认真的
Mom, back off. Seriously.
大家别忘了  我们这是秘密放映
All right, don't forget, secret screening,
所以我们不能让别人看出我们在排队
so we cannot look like a line!
经理马上就要从里面出来下班回家了
The manager's gonna come out pretty soon and go home.
我们只是40几个
We're just 40-some-odd people
刚好站在这里的人
who happen to be standing here.
看看手机  望望天空
So, look at your phones or up at the sky
或者吹个口哨啥的
and whistle or something.
-哦  好吧  像这样吗  -很好
- Oh. Okay. Like this? - Great.
等等  太多系鞋带的了
Wait, wait. Too many shoe tie-ers,
来一个人假装打车
One of you hail a cab.
的士
Taxi!
我该怎么办
What do I do?
继续  继续  进去  绕这儿转一圈
Commit, commit, get in, circle the block.
你好
Hello.
请这边走  才华横溢的小姐
Right this way, talent.
真不敢相信我答应你们了
I can't believe I agreed to this.
那些是从我的玫瑰园里摘的吗
Are those from my rose bush?
今晚你又是名人了
Tonight, you're a celebrity again.
你啥也不用担心
You don't have a worry in the world.
我还真挺担心我的玫瑰花的
Well, I'm worried about my roses.
没事的  没事的  它们可坚强了
They're fine. They're fine. They're resilient!
嗨  小雪
Hi, Yuki!
贝尔彻家的豪华轿车为您服务
Belcher family limo at your service!
你的座位上有一瓶水
You'll notice a bottle of water on your seat.
是为你准备的
That's for you,
鉴于名人比一般人更容易口渴
because celebrities gets thirstier than normal people.
藏在你座位下的芝士饼干
The cheese sticks hidden in the seat...
那些不是给你的
those are not for you.
接下来的车程里
I will now put up the privacy divider
我将为你竖起隐私隔板
for the remainder of your ride.
好了  他走了  让他们进来  快
Okay, he's gone. Get 'em in! Get 'em in!
糟糕  他们来早了
Oh, crap, they're early!
糟糕  我们来早了
Crap, we're early!
现在不能让他们发现对方
They can't see each other yet!
我知道  得先让小雪看电影
I know! First Yuki's got to watch the movie,
感到愧疚  萌生修复父女关系的想法
feel bad and want to repair their relationship!
-我知道  我们的完美计划  -完美无瑕
- I know! Our perfect plan! - Flawless!
我们得赶紧让他进去  阿岛  快来
We got to get him inside! Koji, come on.
我在给凯文签名呢
But I am giving Kevin an autograph.
别管什么凯文了  快进去  我们走
Forget Kevin. Inside, now, let's go!
吉恩  隐私挡板  快
Gene! Privacy screen! Get in there!
你需要隐私  来点隐私
You need privacy! Be private!
-得走快点  快点  -你打我干嘛
- We got to move! Let's move! - Ow, you hit me.
那是...凯文
That was... Kevin.
凯文  走开
Kevin, get away!
走开  凯文
Get away, Kevin!
我走开啦
You got me away!
小心那...
Watch out for the...
好了  隐私结束
Okay, privacy's over.
-接下来是属于你的时间了  -多谢
- You had some you time. - Thanks.
快开始的时候我们再来接你
Okay, we'll come and get you when it's about to start!
等下  为什么不能现在就进去
Wait. Why can't I go in now?
剧场里供演员休息准备的房间
你先在绿房里休息一下
Yeah, just relax and enjoy the green room.
虽然它不绿  也不算个房间
Sorry it's not actually green, or a room.
我可以允许你吃一块芝士饼干
You may have one cheese stick!
乖乖坐在这里
Okay, just sit here and be quiet.
电影开始前
And keep the jacket on your head
别把外套从头上拿下来
till the movie starts.
这里头可冷了
It's very cold in here.
好的  没问题
Okay. Got it. No problem.
观影愉快  小姐
Enjoy the movie, lady!
里面有你哦  给你纸巾
You're in it! And here's some tissues.
遭遇人生转折点的时候特别有用
They're good for when something life-changing happens.
好了  开始了
All right, here we go.
那时候的日本
It was a time in Japan
可怕的怪物会毫无缘由地
when evil monsters would attack
袭击美丽的小村庄
nice little villages for no good reason.
而全日本唯一能够阻止它们的...
And the only force in all of Japan who could stop them...
只有鹰与雏
Hawk & Chick!
上面有个村庄
There's a village up ahead.
也许那里有人需要理发
Maybe there's hair that needs cutting.
但愿那里没有怪物需要对付
And hopefully, no monsters that need defeating.
-这感觉太棒了  -我懂
- This is amazing! - I know!
-我们太牛了  -我们真的很牛
- We're incredible. - We really are.
不  是海藻怪
Oh, no, seaweed monster!
你把我的理发都搞砸了  我可是村长
You're ruining my haircut, and I'm the mayor!
海藻怪  放开我
Seaweed monster, let me go!
你喜欢这电影吗
So, you loving the movie?
不  不怎么喜欢  挺痛苦的
No. Not really. It's kind of painful?
-要不要来点爆米花  -好
- You want some popcorn? - Sure.
终于死了
It is finally dead.
父亲  它还没完全死
Father! It's not all dead!
还有残留势力
Part of it still wishes to fight.
那不是我的声音诶  你觉得呢
That's not how I sound. Is that how I sound?
不是  老天  好像快没电了
No! Oh, God, I think the batteries are dying!
但我们今早才换了新电池啊
But we put new batteries in this morning!
怎么可能这样
How could this happen?
快进  倒退
Fast-forward! Rewind!
快进  倒退  快进  倒退
Fast-forward! Rewind! Fast-forward! Rewind!
也没那么糟
Well, it's not that bad.
也许没人会注意到
Maybe no one will notice.
让把这东西
Let's send this thing
送回...
back to the...
好吧  很糟
Okay, that's really bad.
我们得做点什么
We got to do something!
这儿有麦  看来我们得即兴发挥了
There's a mic. I think we got to wing it.
还好我们对这电影已经烂熟于心了
Good thing we've seen this movie a thousand times.
休想再破坏这村子
No longer will you terrorize this town,
海藻怪
Seaweed Monster.
我们今天就要将你除掉
We are going to weed you out!
糟了  我们需要村民
Crap, we need the villagers!
琳  琳  这里需要你们
Lin! Lin! Psst! We need you guys up here.
-啥  -过来  快
- What? - Come here! Hurry!
那海藻怪去哪儿了
Which way did the Seaweed Monster go?
-那边  -不  是那边
- That way! - No, that way!
怪物  绿的  绿的
Monster! Green! Green!
我看不下去了
I can't do this.
糟糕  她要走了  小雪要走了
Oh, God, she's leaving! Yuki's leaving!
忘了告诉你们  你们的计划没成功
Oh, I forgot to tell you, your plan's not working.
她一点都不喜欢  她自己告诉我的
She's having a terrible time. She told me.
我还以为爆米花能让她感觉好点
I thought the popcorn would make her feel better,
但也没用
but it didn't.
等等  到我了
Hang on, it's my line.
别伤害我  我是村长
Don't hurt me. I'm the mayor.
别伤害我  我是村长  老妈
Don't hurt me. I'm the mayor. Mom!
该死  小雪  你急死我了
Damn it, Yuki, you're killing me!
我们怎么办  该怎么办
What do we do? What do we do?!
等等
Wait.
小雪  别走
Yuki, don't go!
我是说  雏
I mean, Chick.
我知道我们现在正对战海藻怪
I know we're fighting this Seaweed Monster right now,
但我想让你知道我有多爱你  多支持你
but I want you to know how much I love and support you,
即使你...等等
even if you decide... Hold on. Hiya!
在未来的某天决定不再与我一同杀怪
...to stop fighting monsters with me someday and...
转行做会计
do taxes instead.
老鹰  我也想让你知道...
And, Hawk, I want you to know...
即使那种事发生
hiya!... if that ever happens,
应该道歉的也应该是我
it's me who should apologize for leaving!
是我太傻才选择离开你
'Cause I would be dumb to do that.
我怎么不记得有这个桥段
I don't remember this part.
你有觉得演员演技很烂吗
Are the actors really bad?
有  超烂
Yes. They're horrible.
不  我把这房子打得稀巴烂
No! Smash this house!
雏完全不需要道歉
Chick doesn't need to apologize for anything!
她只是个孩子  我再打飞这村民
Chick was just a kid! And I hit this guy!
可是  可是  父女俩怎么可以
But... but... how could a father and daughter not talk
30年不说话呢
for 30 freaking years?!
海藻怪突然
Seaweed Monster suddenly thinks
领悟到了什么
this might be about something else.
我又要捏你了  抱歉
And I'm squeezing you. Sorry about that.
我以后会变成一个完全不一样的人吗
Am I gonna turn into someone completely different someday?
人长大都会这样吗
Is that what happens when you grow up?
-都会...和身边的人分开吗  -听我说
- You... you grow apart? - Listen,
鹰与雏父女俩的事绝不会在我们身上重演
what happened to Hawk and Chick will never happen to us.
我俩这对鹰与雏永远不会30年不说话
This Hawk and this Chick will never not talk for 30 years.
你保证吗
You promise?
当然  露易丝  不  雏
Yes, of course, Louise. I mean, Chick.
外国电影比好莱坞电影难懂好多
Foreign films are so much more complex than Hollywood movies.
我又变回怪物了
I'm the monster again.
我被刺了
I'm getting stabbed.
我...我爆炸了
I'm getting... I exploded.
我不知道我为啥..为啥爆...
I'm not sure why I... I explo...
我死了  我没了
I'm dead. I'm gone.
阿岛  快去和她说话
Koji, talk to her.
-和谁  -小雪啊
- To who? - To Yuki.
我的小雪
My Yuki.
小雪  我...我是你的父亲
Yuki, it's... it's your father speaking.
老爸  你在这儿做什么
Dad? What are you doing here?
你们不说他不会来吗
You said he wasn't gonna be here.
你们骗我
You tricked me.
惊喜哦
Surprise.
小雪  我大老远过来就是想告诉你我很想你
Yuki, please, I've come all this way to tell you I miss you.
我为我所做的一切道歉
I am sorry for everything.
我不是一个好父亲
I have not been a good father.
她开始动心了
Oh, she's thinking about it.
我爱你  我的雏
I love you, little Chick.
爸爸
Oh, Dad.
他打动她了  他打动她了
Oh, he got her. He got her.
我们成功了  我们成功了
We did it. We did it.
这结局比我想的
Wow, that ended up working
好太多了
way better than I thought it would.
跟我想的一模一样
It went about exactly the way I thought it would.
我该送你们回家了  对吗
So I should get you kids home, right?
几点了
What time is it?
-已经过了午夜了  -你们明天要上学吗
- It's after midnight. - Is it a school night?
是的  我明天还有一个大考
Yes, and I have a big test tomorrow.
-几乎半个年级的人都要参加  -抱歉
It's, like, half my grade. Oh, sorry.
哈斯丁经典荣誉出品
Hastings Classics proudly presents:
《鹰与雏》收藏者套装
The Hawk & Chick collector's box set.
包含全套14部电影  讲述日本电影史上
All 14 films, featuring the most celebrated
最负盛名的父女档
father-daughter traveling barber samurais
一边四处为人理发  一边行侠仗义的故事
in the history of Japanese cinema.
所有经典战役都重新灌录成了数字版
All their epic battles have been digitally remastered.
对鹰来说  最难的不是理发
The toughest job for Hawk wasn't cutting hair
也不是对战水母怪物
or defeating a jellyfish monster.
而是独自一人抚养女儿
It was raising a daughter by himself.
现在就订购吧
Order today.
把《鹰与雏》套装带回家
Take the Hawk & Chick box set home to your village.